Guide to the General Photograph Collection: Portraits MSS.PHOTO.0100
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Portraits (General Photograph Collection)
circa 1860-1983
1900-1940
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Harris & Ewing
Barnes, Mary Sheldon, 1850-1898
Brasch, Frederick E. (Frederick Edward), 1875-1967
Newcome, Martha Ewing, 1870-1959
Weston, Otheto, 1895-1990
MSS.PHOTO.0100
9 Linear Feet (16 boxes)
Miscellaneous collection spanning more than a century of portrait photographs depicting over 400 notable people, in many cases signed or inscribed by them.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Various sources, noted when known.
Conditions Governing Access
Open for research. Note that material must be requested at least 36 hours in advance of intended use.
Arrangement
Collection is not in alphabetical order. Some subjects have more than one folder.
Scope and Contents
Spanning one hundred years, this artificial collection of portraits, snapshots, and group photographs features a calvacade of notable figures, including politicians, military leaders, heads of state, journalists, authors, poets, scientists (especially professors of physics, astronomy, and mathematics), explorers, pioneers, labor leaders, musicians, and artists. The identity of some subjects is not always confirmed. Some names do not appear on the print and were from an unknown external source. Others remain unidentified. The majority of photographs are signed (i.e. autographed) or inscribed (used to describe a note to someone in particular). Some have stamps and other notes contemporary to the print and later, including old SUL call numbers. These are not always noted or transcribed. The photographer or studio and its geographic location has been transcribed when known. Most prints are believed to be original, but there a few older copy prints. While most prints are typical early 20th century prints in various mounts, there are also many older cartes-de-visite and cabinet cards, and one Polaroid circa 1980-1983.
This collection was assembled over the life of Stanford Special Collections and includes multiple accessions and donors. Many of them (perhaps a third) came from the famous studio Harris & Ewing and are frequently inscribed to the firm's Martha Ewing, implying that she may have donated them herself. Another significant source of photographs is Stanford faculty, including Frederick Edward Brasch, Melville Best Anderson, Edith R. Mirrielees, and Mary Sheldon Barnes. Some photographs were removed from their original archival papers. For example, mixed throughout the collection are several images from Columbia and the gold mining region of California's Tuolumne County; these are likely separated from the Otheto Weston Gold Country Collection, ca. 1849-1944 (M0029): https://searchworks.stanford.edu/view/4082747. All of these sources are noted where indicated.
Portrait photography; Carte des visite photographs; Cabinet photographs; Harris & Ewing; Barnes, Mary Sheldon, 1850-1898; Brasch, Frederick E. (Frederick Edward), 1875-1967; Newcome, Martha Ewing, 1870-1959; Weston, Otheto, 1895-1990
- Amos and Andy -- Freeman Gosden and C.J. Correll [signed] (Box 1, Folder 1)
  Amos and Andy.
- Howard Ayars (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Francis Berryman (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Albert J. Beveridge, Senator from Indiana: Indianapolis 1922 [signed 1923] (Box 1, Folder 4)
  Beveridge, Albert J. (Albert Jeremiah), 1862-1927
- Edward Nelson Bewley (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Frederick E. Brasch [2 photographs] (Box 1, Folder 6)
  Related Materials
  See also the Frederick E. Brasch papers, 1745-1963 (M0275) https://searchworks.stanford.edu/view/4083165
  Brasch, Frederick E. (Frederick Edward), 1875-1967
- James H. Breasted [signed Edward Thayer Monroe photograph] (Box 1, Folder 7)
  Breasted, James Henry, 1865-1935
- Francis F. Browne [inscribed to Melville Best Anderson May 10, 1909] (Box 1, Folder 8)
  See also the Melville Best Anderson papers, 1926-1930 (MO731): https://searchworks.stanford.edu/view/4083147
  Browne, Francis F. (Francis Fisher), 1843-1913
- Bliss Carman [8 photographs] (Box 1, Folder 9)
  See also the Bliss Carman papers, 1889-1927 (M0081): https://searchworks.stanford.edu/view/4082768
  Carman, Bliss, 1861-1929
- Maria Christina (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Frank Condon [signed 1924] (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Blanche Bates Creel [2 signed photographs] (Box 1, Folder 12)
  Bates, Blanche, 1873-1941
- William C. Dampier 1932 [with letter to Frederick Brasch 1951] (Box 1, Folder 13)
  Dampier, William Cecil Dampier, Sir, 1867-1952
- Harris De Haven Connick [4 photographs] (Box 1, Folder 14)
  Connick, H. D. H. (Harris De Haven), 1873-1965
- Milton [Devalishy?] [photograph of poker game possibly at Bohemian Grove. inscribed by Milton 1930] (Box 1, Folder 15)
  Scope and Contents
  See also unsigned copy in Irvin Cobb folder.
  Bohemian Club (San Francisco, Calif.)
- William Ward Duffield (Box 1, Folder 16)
  Duffield, W. W. (William Ward), 1823-1907
- Paul Drude (Box 1, Folder 17)
  Drude, Paul, 1863-1906
- Thomas Alva Edison [2 photographs, one with Luther Burbank in Sacramento 1915] (Box 1, Folder 18)
  Negative of Edison and Burbank image also enclosed with the following notes: "Burbank and Edison first met in Sacramento in 1914 during P.P.I.E. when Thos. Edison visited the Exposition. Copied From old print given me by Joe [Tavas?]"
  Edison, Thomas A. (Thomas Alva), 1847-1931; Burbank, Luther, 1849-1926
- Frederick W. Goudy [inscribed 1931] (Box 1, Folder 19)
  Goudy, Frederic W. (Frederic William), 1865-1947
- Ulysses S. Grant and Chinese Viceroy Li Hongzhang in Tientsin 1879 [photograph of Chinese landscape and building on reverse of mount] (Box 1, Folder 20)
  Grant, Ulysses S. (Ulysses Simpson), 1822-1885; Li, Hongzhang, 1823-1901
- Johann Georg Hagen S.J. [photograph reproducing two images and a letter, and a page of a scrapbook] (Box 1, Folder 21)
  Hagen, Johann G., 1847-1930
- Sir William Huggins & Lady Margaret I. Huggins [2 photographs] (Box 1, Folder 22)
  Huggins, William, Sir, 1824-1910; Huggins, Lady, 1848-1915
- Orie Johnson [with enclosed inscription] (Box 1, Folder 23)
- James Joyce [snapshots of buildings, books, and Joyce's gravestone] (Box 1, Folder 24)
  Joyce, James, 1882-1941
- Frank R. Kent [inscribed] (Box 2, Folder 1)
  Kent, Frank R. (Frank Richardson), 1877-1958
- Francis V. Keesling [3 group photos] (Box 2, Folder 2)
  1. Souvenir dinner tendered Campaign Committee Municipal Conference, St. Francis Hotel 9/28/1911 [identifications on reverse] -- 2. William Crocker Dinner to Ambassador Chas. S. Warren, Palace Hotel 8/30/1911 -- 3. California Delegation to Republican National Convention
  Stanford holds two collections of Keesling papers: M0100 (https://searchworks.stanford.edu/view/4082770) and M0258 (https://searchworks.stanford.edu/view/4083210)
  Keesling, Francis V. (Francis Valentine)
- Henry W. Longfellow [2 photographs, 1 catalog Illustration] (Box 2, Folder 3)
  Longfellow, Henry Wadsworth, 1807-1882
- Col. Edward Martindale (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Queena Marie [inscribed 1929] (Box 2, Folder 5)
- President William McKinley 1901 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  "President McKinley is shown speaking at Sawtelle when he visited Los Angeles in 1901. Angelenos, looking foward to the visit of president Truman here, recalled today former president's trips." -- newsclipping on frame verso (removed)
  McKinley, William, 1843-1901
- F.R. Moulton [signed 1929] (Box 2, Folder 7)
  Moulton, Forest Ray, 1872-1952
- John O'Shea [signed by Sibyl Anikeeff] (Box 2, Folder 8)
  O'Shea, John, 1876-1956
- Captain See, U.S. Navy (Box 2, Folder 9)
  See, T. J. J., 1866-1962
- Frank Sheridan (signed 1930] (Box 2, Folder 10)
- Otto Struve (Box 2, Folder 11)
- Dr. Lewis Swift [2 photographs] (Box 2, Folder 12)
  Swift, Lewis, 1820-1913
- James Swinnerton [signed as "Jim"] (Box 2, Folder 13)
  Swinnerton, Jimmy, 1875-1974
- Edward Dewitt Taylor [F.N. Schmidt photograph] (Box 2, Folder 14)
  Taylor, Edward DeWitt
- Kate Douglas Wiggin [signed 1912] (Box 2, Folder 15)
  Wiggin, Kate Douglas Smith, 1856-1923
- Wendell Willkie luncheon, group photo at Pelican Camp Bohemia Grove July 26, 1941 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  Willkie, Wendell L. (Wendell Lewis), 1892-1944; Bohemian Club (San Francisco, Calif.).
- Woodrow Wilson with Clemenceau and two other statesmen [in numbered series with below] (Box 2, Folder 17)
  Wilson, Woodrow, 1856-1924
- Woodrow Wilson [3 photographs in numbered series] (Box 2, Folder 18)
- George Loomis [I.W. Taber photograph, San Francisco] (Box 2, Folder 19)
  Loomis, George M.
- Vicente Blasco Ibáñez [Harris & Ewing photograph inscribed to Harris and Ewing February 26, 1920] (Box 3, Folder 1)
  Blasco Ibáñez, Vicente, 1867-1928
- Senator Nelson W. Aldrich [Harris & Ewing photograph] (Box 3, Folder 2)
  Aldrich, Nelson W. (Nelson Wilmarth), 1841-1915
- John Burroughs [signed Harris & Ewing photograph] (Box 3, Folder 3)
- Admiral Richard Byrd [Harris & Ewing photograph] (Box 3, Folder 4)
  Byrd, Richard Evelyn, 1888-1957
- Joseph G. Cannon [Harris & Ewing photograph inscribed to Martha Ewing January 24, 1906] (Box 3, Folder 5)
  Cannon, Joseph Gurney, 1836-1926
- Otto Carmichael [Harris & Ewing photograph] (Box 3, Folder 6)
- Andrew Carnegie [Harris & Ewing photograph] (Box 3, Folder 7)
  Carnegie, Andrew, 1835-1919
- Senator Thomas H. Carter [Harris & Ewing photograph] (Box 3, Folder 8)
  Carter, Thomas Henry, 1854-1911
- Irvin S. Cobb [Harris & Ewing photograph] (Box 3, Folder 9)
  Cobb, Irvin S. (Irvin Shrewsbury), 1876-1944
- President Calvin Coolidge [Harris & Ewing photograph, two copies, one inscribed to Martha Ewing May 1921] (Box 3, Folder 10)
  Coolidge, Calvin, 1872-1933
- Grace Coolidge [Harris & Ewing photograph inscribed to Martha Ewing on attached strip of paper] (Box 3, Folder 11)
  Coolidge, Grace Goodhue, 1879-1957
- Louis A. Coolidge [Harris & Ewing photograph] (Box 3, Folder 12)
  Coolidge, Louis A. (Louis Arthur), 1861-1925
- Herbert Cory [Harris & Ewing photograph] (Box 3, Folder 13)
  Cory, Herbert E. (Herbert Ellsworth), 1883-1947
- William Jennings Bryan [Harris & Ewing photograph] (Box 3, Folder 14)
  Bryan, William Jennings, 1860-1925
- Frank T. Burd [Harris & Ewing photograph] (Box 3, Folder 15)
- Admiral Amundsen [Harris & Ewing photograph] (Box 3, Folder 16)
  Amundsen, Roald, 1872-1928
- Theodore Roosevelt and family [2 photographs, one Harris & Ewing photograph inscribed to Martha Ewing June 2, 1908, one R.W. Thacher photograph of Edith and Ethel Roosevelt 1900] (Box 3, Folder 17)
- Gene Buck [print of portrait by James Montgomery Flagg inscribed to "Sam"], 1937 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  Immediate Source of Acquisition
  Harris & Ewing collection
- Astrid, Queen of Belgium [Harris & Ewing photograph] (Box 4, Folder 1)
  Astrid, Queen, consort of Léopold III, King of the Belgians, 1905-1935
- Arthur J. Balfour [Harris & Ewing photograph. two copies, one mounted on chipboard] (Box 4, Folder 2)
  Balfour, Arthur James, 1848-1930
- Alexander Graham Bell [possibly signed Harris & Ewing photograph] (Box 4, Folder 3)
  Bell, Alexander Graham, 1847-1922
- Senator William E. Borah [Harris & Ewing photograph] (Box 4, Folder 4)
  Borah, William Edgar, 1865-1940
- Senator Frank B. Brandegee [Harris & Ewing photograph] (Box 4, Folder 5)
  Brandegee, Frank B. (Frank Bosworth), 1864-1924
- Arthur Brisbane [signed Harris & Ewing photograph] (Box 4, Folder 6)
  Brisbane, Arthur, 1864-1936
- Samuel G. Blythe [Harris & Ewing photograph] (Box 4, Folder 7)
  Blythe, Samuel G. (Samuel George), 1868-1947
- Admiral Cary T. Grayson [Harris & Ewing photograph] (Box 4, Folder 8)
  Grayson, Cary T. (Cary Travers), 1878-1938
- William Green [Harris & Ewing photograph signed as W. Green, President, American Federation of Labor] (Box 4, Folder 9)
  Green, William, 1870-1952
- Mrs. Warren G. Harding [Harris & Ewing photograph signed as Florence Kling Harding on attached strip of paper] (Box 4, Folder 10)
  Harding, Florence Kling, 1860-1924
- Warren G. Harding [Harris & Ewing photograph] (Box 4, Folder 11)
  Harding, Warren G. (Warren Gamaliel), 1865-1923
- Warren G. Harding [Harris & Ewing photograph inscribed to Martha Ewing] (Box 4, Folder 12)
- William Randolph Hearst [Harris & Ewing photograph] (Box 4, Folder 13)
  Hearst, William Randolph, 1863-1951
- Frank T. Heffelfinger [Lee Brothers photograph inscribed "Hit One For Me Sam"] (Box 4, Folder 14)
- Victor Herbert, Irving Berlin and John Philip Sousa [Harris & Ewing photograph] (Box 4, Folder 15)
  Herbert, Victor; Sousa, John Philip, 1854-1932; Berlin, Irving, 1888-1989
- Paul R. Heyl [Harris & Ewing photograph], 1925 (Box 4, Folder 16)
  Heyl, Paul R.
- James C. Hooe [signed Harris & Ewing photograph] (Box 4, Folder 17)
- Lou Henry Hoover [signed Harris & Ewing photograph] (Box 4, Folder 18)
  Hoover, Lou Henry, 1874-1944
- Bohemian Club posed group photograph [Gabriel Moulin photograph, San Francisco signed by Thomas Moulin], circa early 1960s (Box 4, Folder 19)
- George M. Loomis [inscribed E. Goldowsky photograph] (Box 4, Folder 20)
  Harris & Ewing collection.
- Lloyd George [Harris & Ewing photograph] (Box 5, Folder 1)
- Vice-President John Nance Garner [Harris & Ewing photograph] (Box 5, Folder 2)
  Garner, John Nance, 1868-1967
- Mrs. John N. Garner [Harris & Ewing photograph] (Box 5, Folder 3)
  Garner, Mariette, 1869-1948
- Henry Ford [Harris & Ewing photograph] (Box 5, Folder 4)
  Ford, Henry, 1863-1947
- General Foch [Harris & Ewing photograph] (Box 5, Folder 5)
  Foch, Ferdinand, 1851-1929
- Senator Joseph B. Foraker [Harris & Ewing photograph] (Box 5, Folder 6)
  Foraker, Joseph Benson, 1846-1917
- James Farley, Postmaster General [Harris & Ewing photograph] (Box 5, Folder 7)
  Farley, James A. (James Aloysius), 1888-1976
- Dwight Eisenhower [2 Harris & Ewing photographs, one with Mrs. Eisenhower] (Box 5, Folder 8)
  Eisenhower, Dwight D. (Dwight David), 1890-1969
- Walt Disney [Harris & Ewing photograph] (Box 5, Folder 9)
  Disney, Walt, 1901-1966
- Admiral Dewey [2 photographs, one Harris & Ewing photo inscribed to Edward Lee [illeg.] and one Linedinst photograph, Washington, D.C.] (Box 5, Folder 10)
  Dewey, George, 1837-1917
- Senator Chauncey M. Depew [Harris & Ewing photograph] (Box 5, Folder 11)
  Depew, Chauncey M. (Chauncey Mitchell), 1834-1928
- Jo Davidson [Harris & Ewing photograph] (Box 5, Folder 12)
  Davidson, Jo, 1883-1952
- Senator Alfred Kittredge [Harris & Ewing photograph] (Box 5, Folder 13)
  Kittredge, Alfred B. (Alfred Beard), 1861-1911
- Fannie Hurst [Harris & Ewing photograph] (Box 5, Folder 15)
  Hurst, Fannie, 1889-1968
- Senator Hiram W. Johnson [signed 1917 Harris & Ewing photograph] (Box 5, Folder 14)
  Johnson, Hiram, 1866-1945
- Senator William Hughes [Harris & Ewing photograph] (Box 5, Folder 16)
  Hughes, William, 1872-1916
- Chaing Hsueh-Liang [Harris & Ewing photograph with Chinese writing on two attached strips of paper, possibly an inscription] (Box 6, Folder 1)
  Zhang, Xueliang, 1901-2001
- Joaquin Miller [Harris & Ewing photograph inscribed to Martha Ewing] (Box 6, Folder 2)
  Miller, Joaquin, 1837-1913
- Kathleen Norris [Harris & Ewing photograph] (Box 6, Folder 3)
  Norris, Kathleen Thompson, 1880-1966
- Richard V. Oulahan [signed Harris & Ewing photograph] (Box 6, Folder 4)
  Oulahan, Richard V. (Richard Victor), 1867-1931
- Ignacy Paderewski [Harris & Ewing photograph] (Box 6, Folder 5)
  Paderewski, Ignace Jan, 1860-1941
- Admiral Peary [Harris & Ewing photograph] (Box 6, Folder 6)
  Peary, Robert E. (Robert Edwin), 1856-1920
- General John J. Pershing [Harris & Ewing photograph] (Box 6, Folder 7)
  Pershing, John J. (John Joseph), 1860-1948
- Grantland Rice [signed Harris & Ewing photograph] (Box 6, Folder 8)
  Rice, Grantland, 1880-1954
- Mary Roberts Rinehart [Harris & Ewing photograph] (Box 6, Folder 9)
  Rinehart, Mary Roberts, 1876-1958
- Governor Albert C. Ritchie [Harris & Ewing photograph] (Box 6, Folder 10)
  Ritchie, Albert C. (Albert Cabell), 1876-1936
- Kenneth L. Roberts [Harris & Ewing photograph] (Box 7, Folder 1)
  Roberts, Kenneth L., active 1918
- John D. Rockefeller [Harris & Ewing photograph] (Box 7, Folder 2)
  Rockefeller, John D. (John Davison), 1839-1937
- Woodrow Wilson & group [Harris & Ewing photograph] (Box 7, Folder 3)
- Franklin Delano Roosevelt [Harris & Ewing photograph inscribed to Martha Ewing] (Box 7, Folder 4)
  Roosevelt, Franklin D. (Franklin Delano), 1882-1945
- Eleanor Roosevelt [Harris & Ewing photograph] (Box 7, Folder 5)
  Roosevelt, Eleanor, 1884-1962
- Franklin K. Lane [Harris & Ewing photograph] (Box 7, Folder 6)
  Lane, Franklin K.
- Elihu Root [Harris & Ewing photograph] (Box 7, Folder 7)
  Root, Elihu, 1845-1937
- Ring Lardner [Harris & Ewing photograph] (Box 7, Folder 8)
  Lardner, Ring, 1885-1933
- King of Belgium [Harris & Ewing photograph] (Box 7, Folder 9)
  Albert I, King of the Belgians, 1875-1934
- Fulton Lewis Jr. [Harris & Ewing photograph] (Box 7, Folder 10)
  Lewis, Fulton, 1903-1966
- Charles Lindbergh [Harris & Ewing photograph] (Box 7, Folder 11)
  Lindbergh, Charles A. (Charles Augustus), 1902-1974
- Henry Cabot Lodge [Harris & Ewing photograph] (Box 7, Folder 12)
  Lodge, Henry Cabot, 1850-1924
- Nicholas Longworth [Harris & Ewing photograph] (Box 7, Folder 13)
  Longworth, Nicholas, 1869-1931
- Alice Roosevelt Longworth and Pauline [Harris & Ewing photograph] (Box 7, Folder 14)
  Longworth, Alice Roosevelt, 1884-1980
- Ramsay MacDonald [Harris & Ewing photograph] (Box 7, Folder 15)
  MacDonald, James Ramsay, 1866-1937
- Guglielmo Marconi [Harris & Ewing photograph] (Box 7, Folder 16)
  Marconi, Guglielmo, 1874-1937
- Peter Clark MacFarlane [Harris & Ewing photograph inscribed to Martha Ewing Newcome 1919] (Box 7, Folder 17)
  MacFarlane, Peter Clark, 1871-1924
- Queen Marie of Romania [Harris & Ewing photograph] (Box 7, Folder 18)
  Marie, Queen, consort of Ferdinand I, King of Romania, 1875-1938
- Hamilton W. Mabie [Harris & Ewing photograph inscribed to Martha Ewing 1909] (Box 7, Folder 19)
  Mabie, Hamilton Wright, 1846-1916
- Dr. Charles Mayo [Harris & Ewing photograph] (Box 7, Folder 20)
  Mayo, Charles H. (Charles Horace), 1865-1939
- John T. McCutcheon [Harris & Ewing photograph inscribed to Martha Ewing with a small illustration 1907] (Box 7, Folder 21)
  McCutcheon, John T. (John Tinney), 1870-1949
- Charles Michelson [Harris & Ewing photograph] (Box 8, Folder 1)
  Michelson, Charles, 1869-1948
- Mrs. Woodrow Wilson - Second [Harris & Ewing photograph] (Box 8, Folder 2)
  Wilson, Edith Bolling Galt, 1872-1961
- Arthur James Balfour [Harris & Ewing photograph] (Box 8, Folder 3)
- Senator Arthur H. Vandenberg [Harris & Ewing photograph] (Box 8, Folder 4)
  Vandenberg, Arthur H. (Arthur Hendrick), 1884-1951
- Gene Tunney [Harris & Ewing photograph] (Box 8, Folder 5)
  Tunney, Gene, 1897-1978
- James S. Sherman [Harris & Ewing photograph inscribed to Martha Ewing 1908] (Box 8, Folder 6)
  Sherman, J. S. (James Schoolcraft), 1855-1912
- Mrs. William Howard Taft [Harris & Ewing photograph] (Box 8, Folder 7)
  Taft, Helen Herron, 1861-1943
- Taft visit to Hawaii [2 photographs, copy prints] (Box 8, Folder 8)
  President & Mrs. Taft; Mrs. Taft, Nicholas Longworth and Alice Roosevelt. Gift of H.J. Dean.
  Taft, William H. (William Howard), 1857-1930; Taft, Helen Herron, 1861-1943; Longworth, Nicholas, 1869-1931; Longworth, Alice Roosevelt, 1884-1980
- Harry S. Truman [Harris & Ewing photograph inscribed to Martha Ewing] (Box 9, Folder 1)
  Truman, Harry S., 1884-1972
- Prince of Wales [Harris & Ewing photograph] (Box 9, Folder 2)
  Windsor, Edward, Duke of, 1894-1972
- Henry Watterson [Harris & Ewing photograph] (Box 9, Folder 3)
  Watterson, Henry, 1840-1921
- H.G. Wells [Harris & Ewing photograph inscribed to Martha Ewing 1921] (Box 9, Folder 4)
  Wells, H. G. (Herbert George), 1866-1946
- Chief Justice White [Harris & Ewing photograph] (Box 9, Folder 5)
  White, Edward Douglass, 1845-1921
- Robert J. Wynne [Harris & Ewing photograph] (Box 9, Folder 6)
  Wynne, Robert John, 1851-1922
- Unidentified Harris and Ewing photograph (Box 9, Folder 7)
- Unidentified Harris and Ewing photograph (Box 9, Folder 8)
- Unidentified Harris and Ewing photograph (Box 9, Folder 9)
- Unidentified Harris and Ewing photograph (Box 9, Folder 10)
- Yuan Shikai [Chinese writing on borders. Fu Sheng photograph, Tientsin], 1912 (Box 9, Folder 11)
  Yuan, Shikai, 1859-1916
- Unidentified Harris and Ewing photograph (Box 9, Folder 12)
- Unidentified Harris and Ewing photograph (Box 9, Folder 13)
- Wendell Wilkie [Harris & Ewing photograph] (Box 10, Folder 1)
  Willkie, Wendell L. (Wendell Lewis), 1892-1944
- William Howard Taft [2 Harris & Ewing photographs, one inscribed to Martha Ewing 1909] (Box 10, Folder 2)
  Taft, William H. (William Howard), 1857-1930
- Dorothy Thompson [Harris & Ewing photograph] (Box 10, Folder 3)
- Mark Sullivan [Harris & Ewing photograph] (Box 10, Folder 4)
  Sullivan, Mark, 1874-1952
- Raymond Gram Swing [Harris & Ewing photograph] (Box 10, Folder 5)
  Swing, Raymond, 1887-1968
- Richard Nixon [Harris & Ewing photograph inscribed to Martha Ewing Newcome] (Box 10, Folder 6)
  Nixon, Richard M. (Richard Milhous), 1913-1994
- Simon Newcomb [Harris & Ewing photograph] (Box 10, Folder 7)
  Newcomb, Simon, 1835-1909
- Herbert Hoover [2 Harris & Ewing photographs, one signed] (Box 10, Folder 8)
  Hoover, Herbert, 1874-1964
- Albert Einstein [2 Harris & Ewing photographs] (Box 10, Folder 9)
  Einstein, Albert, 1879-1955
- Unidentified Harris and Ewing photograph (Box 10, Folder 10)
- Unidentified Pirie Mac Donald photograph [inscribed to Sam, possibly by Emmett?] (Box 10, Folder 11)
- Unidentified photograph of two men and two women on train or street car circa 1940s (Box 10, Folder 12)
- Unidentified Harris and and Ewing Photograph (Box 10, Folder 13)
- Orie Johnson [photograph of painting by Haig Patigian 1944, inscribed to Sam and Martha] (Box 10, Folder 14)
- Dr. C.G. Abbot [G.V. Buck photograph, Washington, D.C.] (Box 11, Folder 1)
  Abbot, C. G. (Charles Greeley), 1872-1973
- Bristow Adams [Franklin photograph, Palo Alto. Inscribed "Yours Without a Struggle"] (Box 11, Folder 2)
  Adams, Bristow, 1875-1957
- Walter S. Adams (Box 11, Folder 3)
  Newton Collection
  Adams, Walter S. (Walter Sydney), 1876-1956
- George Ade [Harris & Ewing photograph signed 1908] (Box 11, Folder 4)
  Ade, George, 1866-1944
- Louis Agassiz [2 photographs, one by Bradley & Rulofson, one by Habenicht, both in San Francisco] (Box 11, Folder 5)
  Agassiz, Louis, 1807-1873
- Robert G. Aitken [signed 1928] (Box 11, Folder 6)
  Aitken, Robert Grant, 1864-1951
- Bertram Alanson [2 photographs, one by Moulin, San Francisco 1957] (Box 11, Folder 7)
  Alanson was the donor of Stanford's William Somerset Maugham collection.
  Alanson, Bertram E., 1877-1958
- Louisa May Alcott [James Notman photograph, Boston] (Box 11, Folder 8)
  Alcott, Louisa May, 1832-1888
- Alfonso XII, King of Spain [L. Joliot photograph, Paris] (Box 11, Folder 9)
  Alfonso XII, King of Spain, 1857-1885
- Matthew Arnold [Elliot & Fry photograph, London] (Box 11, Folder 10)
  Arnold, Matthew, 1822-1888
- J.K. Hunter - Nate Arnold - Jim Carey. Columbia. Taken in SF While Staying at Lick House [Bradley & Rulofson photograph, San Francisco] (Box 11, Folder 11)
  Columbia (Calif.)
- S.I. Bailey [signed Marshall photograph, Cambridge] (Box 11, Folder 12)
  Bailey, Solon I. (Solon Irving), 1854-
- Myrna Baldwin [Coules Palace Studio photograph, Los Angeles, "Dr. Martindale" written on verso] (Box 11, Folder 13)
- M.A. Banahan (now Brady) 1862 [Sewell's photograph, Sonora], circa 1863 (Box 11, Folder 14)
  Banahan (1849-1925) was one of two daughters born to Mary Teresa Kilduff who emigrated to Sonora, California from Ireland with her children after the death of her husband. Margaret married Matthew T. Brady of Columbia, California in 1869.